The game is played in the blink of an eye.
Fastball is a documentary film directed by Jonathan Hock.
Since 1912, baseball has been a game obsessed with statistics and speed.
Thrown at upwards of 100 miles per hour, a fastball moves too quickly for
human cognition and accelerates into the realm of intuition.
Fastball is a look at how the game at its highest levels of achievement transcends logic and
even skill, becoming the primal struggle for man to control the uncontrollable.
Narrator, played by Kevin Costner.
Self (archive footage), played by Hank Aaron.
Self (archive footage), played by Nolan Ryan.
Self, played by Derek Jeter.
Self, played by Denard Span.
Self (archive footage), played by Craig Kimbrel.
Fastball is an American rock band.
It was formed in Austin, Texas, in 1992.
The band originally called themselves Magneto U.S.A., and changed
their name after signing with Hollywood Records.
In 1998, their album All the Pain Money Can Buy reached platinum sales within six
months of its release, and stayed on the Billboard 200 chart for a year.
Their songs "The Way" and "Out of My Head" reached No.
14 on Billboard's Adult Alternative Songs chart, respectively.
In addition, the group has been nominated for two Grammy Awards – Best Rock Performance by a Duo or Group
with Vocal for "The Way", and Best Long Form Music Video for their promotional video "The Way".
They also received five The Austin Chronicle awards: 1998's Album of the Year, Best
Video, Best Single/EP, Band of the Year, and 1995's Best Pop Band.
In late 2021, Fastball started a Patreon campaign supporting the release of new
music, as well as demos of their songs and the stories behind them.